Finding Aid of the Dave Berkman Papers, 1958-2016
University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee Libraries, Archives Department
Dave Berkman Papers, 1958-2016
Berkman, Dave.
UWM Manuscript Collection 347
[insert size] cubic ft. ([insert #] boxes, including x audio cassettes and x video cassettes)
University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee Libraries, Archives Department
Papers of former UWM professor and media critic Dave Beckman consisting of articles, including copies of his Shepherd Express “Media Musings,” news clippings, correspondence, and an extensive set of radio broadcasts, largely Wisconsin Public Radio recordings.
Dave Berkman (1934-2015) was a college professor and media critic. Berkman taught mass communications at UW-Milwaukee, among other univeristies. For many years he wrote a column called "Media Musing" for the Shepherd Express, a Milwaukee alternative paper. He also hosted Wisconsin Public Radio's "Media Talk" show for 13 years.
Berkman was a liberal, a civil rights activist, and a free speech absolutist, and served on the state boards of the ACLU in Wisconsin and Connecticut, as well as on the Corporation for Public Broadcasting's Minority Task Force. Berkman was a member of the National Association of Educational Broadcasters, and advocated protecting Public Broadcasting's independence from political threats. He was a man of strong opinions who loved politics and argument.
The paper files largely consist of correspondence, copies of Berkman's "Media Musings" in Milwaukee's Shepherd Express alternative newspaper, publications and articles, and clipping files. The collection also includes Berkman's 1963 dissertation, as well as various reports, including information about the work of the Corporation for Public Broadcasting's Minority Task Force on which Berkman served.
The radio broadcasts, largely Wisconsin Public Radio recordings, ...
The files are arranged into the following series:
Paper Files, 1958-2016
Radio Broadcasts, dates
Alternate Format
Related Material in the UWM Libraries
UW-Milwaukee Dept. of Mass Communication UWM Archival Collection 179
UW-Milwaukee University Relations Records UWM Archival Collection 96
Administrative/Restriction Information
There are no access restrictions on the materials, and the collection is open to all members of the public in accordance with state law.
Margarita Dusek donated the collection to the Archives in September and November 2016 (accession 2016-015).
Contents List
- Records, 1958-2016, UWM Manuscript Collection 347; cubic ft. ( boxes, including x audio cassettes and x video cassettes) electronic
  - 1. Paper Files, 1958-2016
    - Address, Medgar Evers College, 1979 (Box 3)
    - Clippings, 1958-2016 (Box 3)
    - Corporation for Public Broadcasting's Minority Task Force, 1978-1981 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, 1960-2015 (Box 1)
    - Dissertation, 1963 (Box 3)
    - ITV Business Development Project, 1969 (Box 4)
    - Manuscript, Report, and Survey, 1978-1989 (Box 3)
    - Media Musings, Shepherd Express, 1989-2006 (Box 2)
    - Publications/Articles, 1962-2006 (Box 2)
    - Vita, 2010 (Box 3)
  - 2. Radio Broadcasts
    - Tim Russert's Ethics, 03 February 2006, 1 digital audio file (0:51:27 (approx)) (Electronic 140)
      With Joe Fontaine, Columnist, Ripon College Days.